[i]Description by Adler Drei Gang:[/i]

[h1]Realistic Mars[/h1]

This Mod adds a bunch of new gameplay and diﬃculty options for you to choose to make surviving Mars more of a challenge. 
Changing Settings reqiures Mod Config by Waywocket. Found here:
http://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1340775972

[list]
[*][b]Wind Fluctuation [/b]
The winds of the martian surface now inﬂuence the power outputs of your windmills. You can’t rely on wind power alone now as it’s output is inconsistant and you need to supplement it with auxiliary power. 

[*][b]Realistic Batteries[/b]
Polymer battery capacity reduced by 30% from vanilla. Cable faults will suck your batteries dry especially during martian nights: use power switches to isolate your power grid from each other before you found your colony empty of juice.

[*][b]Large Solar Panels Maintenance requires Electronics[/b]
Large solar panels maintenance changed from 1 metal to 0.2 electronics. Now the settling game is not a question of balancing your polymers and machine parts, but electronics as well: Do you import from Earth all three resources or will you rely on small solar panels to ease the maintenance of your electricity producers?

[*][b]Disallow Breakthroughs[/b]
Breakthroughs are a boon and a game-changer: with this option you only get 4 (3 from a Wonder and one from the mystery), making each Realistic Mars game diﬀerent after the mid-game.

[*][b]Disallow Outsourcing[/b]
Mars is quite far and the communication lag of 6 to 22 minutes prevents your colony from doing their research live with Earth. Build research labs so your scientists can set up copies of Earth servers on the red planet to do their crucial work. No more beelining a Tech you need now by outsourcing : get that RC Explorer looking around the map for research anomalies, but will you help him out by spending your precious electronics to set up sensor towers ?

[*][b]Rocket Travel Time increased[/b]
It now takes 5 sols instead of 1 for rockets to make the Earth-Mars. Every supply cargo is now a choice you need to commit to. Do you import much needed resources or do you trust your colony to sustain itself and choose a passenger rocket ? Sponsors starting with more than one rocket are now much more valuable and saving funds to buy a second or third rocket is a milestone in itself. You now need to work around Dust storms preventing rocket launch or planetfall.

[*][b]Less Colonists per Rocket[/b]
Choose the cream of the crop from your applicants. Make sure they are never earthsick, suicidal, starving, suﬀocating or thirsty: it takes a long time to get new colonists on Mars and you only have a few per trip.

[*][b]Funding Gains Reduced[/b]
Every 5 resources more you choose to import is a choice you have to commit to. Get a moisture prefab or gamble on ﬁnding a water deposit that will need machine parts ? Or maybe rush for a rare metal extractor and hope you can export enough at the next rocket launch.

[*][b]Food Production Rebalance[/b]
The three different food production buildings now fulfill distinctly different roles. Will you rely on specialists working around the clock in your hydroponics farms, low intensity farming or automated fungal farms?
[/list]


[h1][i]Recommended Settings[/i][/h1]

[b]Challenge Mode[/b]
Realistic Batteries ON, Solar Change OFF, 80% Funding Gains, 8 Colonists per Rocket, 500% Travel Time, Allow Outsourcing and Breakthroughs. 

[b]Death on Mars[/b]
Mod default Settings as in the Picture. 


[u]Enjoy and please leave a comment if you have suggestions.[/u]
Yours Spannbeton

[i]P.S.:
A shoutout to all the people in the Surviving Mars Modding Community who made this possible. [/i]